Guide to the Benét Family Papers, 1803-1970
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES I. LAURA BENÉT, 1873-1970
  - Manuscripts of Other Writers
    - Barker, Elsa - The Scab, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.29)
    - Barker, Elsa - The Secret Companions, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.30)
    - Barker, Elsa - This Book, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.31)
    - Barker, Elsa - Wayna, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.32)
    - Barker, Elsa - Virginia, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.33)
    - Barker, Elsa - Barker, Elsa – Reviews of Works, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.34)
    - Barker, Elsa - Barker, Elsa – TS submitted to Treasury Department, undated; (TS) (Folder 11.35)
    - Barker, Elsa - Fragments, including The Secret Companions, Virginia, The Dragon’s Left Eye, The Alligator Puzzle, undated; (TS) (Folders 11.36-11.40)
    - Barker, Elsa - Poems, misc., undated; (TS) (Folders 11.41-11.50)
    - Barker, Elsa - Unidentified, undated; (TS) (Folders 11.51-11.58)
    - Garvin, [?] -Description of transcontinental trip, 1946; (MS) (Folder 12.1)
    - Bharati, Baba - Jim, Books One & Two, undated; (TS) (Folder 12.6)
    - Sikelianos, Anghelos - Akritan Songs, undated; (TS) (Folder 12.2)
    - Sikelianos, Anghelos - The Awakener, undated; (TS) (Folders 12.3-12.4)
    - Sikelianos, Anghelos - The Death of Digenis, undated; (TS) (Folder 12.5)
    - Winthrop, John - Poem, On Duty, undated; (MS) (Folder 22.16)
- SERIES II. WILLIAM ROSE BENÉT, 1884-1936
  - Correspondence - Incoming
    - Bacon, Leonard, undated (Folder 13.12)
    - Benét, James Walker, Jr., undated (Folder 20.12)
    - Benét, James and Kathleen, 1927, 1936 (Folder 13.13)
    - Benét, Laurence, 1908, 1915 (Folder 20.22)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, undated (Folder 13.14)
    - Benét, Teresa Thompson, undated (Folders 21.3-21.4)
    - Fisher, Alfred High, 1915-1921 (Folder 13.15)
    - Frost, Robert (includes card from Frances Frost), undated (Folder 13.16)
    - Frost, Robert, 1921 May (Folder 13.17)
    - Miller, Ben, 1924-1925 (Folder 13.18)
    - Morley, Christopher, 1916 (Folder 13.19)
    - Morley, Kit, 1919 (Folder 13.20)
    - Noyes, Alfred, 1915 (Folder 13.21)
    - Publishers, including Harper & Bros., Yale Review, Harrison Smith, Inc., 1905-1932 (Folder 13.22)
    - Rose, Mary Lee, 1906 (Folder 13.23)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1918 (Folder 13.24)
    - Miscellaneous friends and associates, 1904-1936 (Folders 13.25-13.29)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing
    - Benét, Laura, 1904-1936 (Folder 13.8)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1903-1904 (Folder 13.9)
    - Benét, Teresa Thompson, 1918 (Folder 19.18)
    - Rose, Mary Lee, 1896-1913 (Folder 13.10)
    - to miscellaneous family members including James Walker Benét and Frances Rose Benét, 1884-1924 (Folder 13.11)
  - Correspondence to and from Teresa Thompson Benét
    - from family members including Frances Rose and James Walker Benét, 1913-1917 (Folders 19.15-19.17)
    - to family members including Mary Lee Rose, Agnes Mahon, Laura Benét, Frances Rose and James Walker Benét, 1912-1917 (Folders 19.19-19.21)
    - from Norris, Kathleen Thompson (Teresa's sister) to family members, undated (Folders 19.22-19.29)
  - Writings
    - The Enlisted Man, 1905; (MS, including notations) (Folder 13.33)
    - Hoodman Blind, A Novel in Verse, undated; (TS) (Folder 13.34)
    - Notes, undated; (TS) (Folder 13.35)
    - Sesfina (poem), undated; (TS) (Folder 13.36)
    - The Shore Road, undated; (MS, including notations) (Folder 13.37)
    - Poetry, clippings, undated (Folder 13.38)
    - Poetry, including To a Falcon, The Joke, Mimi and the Foreboding Frost, Frustrate Boast, undated; (TS) (Folder 13.39)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Receipt, golf score book (with sketch by WRB), 1901 (Folder 13.30)
    - Receipts, invoices, Poetry Society membership card, 1918 (Folder 13.31)
    - Notes, including undated Christmas list (Folder 13.32)
    - War Department memoranda, contracts with Yale University Press, 1914-1918 (Folder 13.40)
    - Insurance policy, 1912 (Folder 27.6)
- SERIES III. STEPHEN VINCENT BENÉT, 1905-1940s
  - Correspondence - Incoming
    - Alanova, Kyra, 1924 (Folder 13.1)
    - Benét, Rosemary Carr, 1939-1940s (Folder 20.23)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1916 (Folder 13.2)
    - Miscellaneous correspondents, including Aggie Mahon, Laura Walker Benét, 1905-1940s (Folder 13.3)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing
    - to Benét, Frances Rose, 1912 (Folder 13.4)
    - to Rose, Mary Lee, undated (Folder 13.5)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Membership confirmation, Mory’s Association, 1916 (Folder 13.6)
    - Little Golightly, The Elks Magazine, 1930 (Folder 13.7)
- SERIES IV. THE PARENTS OF LAURA, WILLIAM, AND STEPHEN, 1810-1942
  - JAMES WALKER BENÉT
    - Correspondence - Incoming
      - Correspondence from friends, family and associates, 1891-1927 (Folders 18.1-18.5)
      - Goethals, George Washington, 1882 (Folder 18.6)
      - from Benét, Laurence, 1886-1905 (Folder 20.18)
      - from Cox, Margaret, 1917-1918 (Folder 20.26)
    - Correspondence - Outgoing
      - to misc. family members, including Teresa Thompson, James Walker Benét, Jr., 1895-1915 (Folder 19.1)
      - to friends, associates, 1895-1916 (Folder 19.2)
      - to Benét, Frances Rose, 1818-1927 (Folders 19.1-19.7)
      - to Benét, Laura, 1916-1927 (Folder 18.12)
      - to Benét, William Rose, 1898-1917 (Folders 18.13-18.14)
      - to Rose, Mary Lee, 1902-1914 (Folder 19.8)
      - to Miller, Ben, 1920-1927 (Folders 18.7-18.10)
    - Miscellaneous
      - An Autobiography, with footnotes by his younger brother, undated; (TS) (Box 23)
      - Journal, [James Walker Benét?], 1920 (Folder 22.18)
      - Centennial International Exhibition - Stock certificate, 1926 (Folder 26.3)
      - Watervliet Arsenal Bids you Welcome to the May Day Fete, 1919 (Folder 18.15)
  - FRANCES NEILL ROSE BENÉT
    - Correspondence - Incoming
      - From miscellaneous friends and associates, 1871-1942 (Folders 14.1-14.23)
      - Benét, Laurence, 1880-1938 (Folder 20.17)
      - Rose, Mary Lee, 1898-1906 (Folders 14.24-14.26)
    - Correspondence - Outgoing
      - to miscellaneous family members, including Elizabeth Neill Rose, Betsy Jane[?], 1929 (Folder 15.1)
      - to Benét, James Walker, 1885-1915 (Folders 15.2-15.11)
      - to Benét, William Rose, includes letter regarding WRB’s probation from Yale University, 1905-1919 (Folders 15.12-15.18)
      - to Mahon, Agnes, 1905-1929 (Folder 15.19)
      - to Rose, Mary Lee and William, 1906-1908 (Folder 16.1)
      - to Rose, Mary Lee, 1810-1917 (Folders 16.2-16.30)
    - Writings
      - Journals, 1903-1940 (Folders 17.1-17.16)
      - A Woman, a Horse and a Dead Man, undated; (MS) (Folder 17.17)
      - Virtue Is It’s Own Reward, undated; (TS, MS) (Folder 17.18)
    - Finances
      - Business records, including invoices, bank receipts, banking correspondence, check registers, 1875-1939 (Folders 21.6-21.9)
    - Correspondence between extended Neill/Rose family members
      - Mahon, A.M., correspondence to Rose, Mary Lee, 1867-1885 (Folder 20.27)
      - Mahon, David and Elizabeth, correspondence to, 1812-1872 (Folder 27.1)
      - Neill, Catherine, correspondence to, undated (Folder 27.4)
      - Neill, David, correspondence to, 1820 (Folder 20.28)
      - Neill, Elizabeth, correspondence to, 1916-1925 (Folders 21.1-21.2)
      - Neill, Sophia, correspondence to, undated (Folder 20.29)
      - Neill, William, correspondence to Rose, Mary Lee, 1852-1858 (Folder 20.30)
      - Rose, Agnes, correspondence to, 1866-1929 (Folders 20.31-20.33)
      - Rose, Mary Lee, correspondence to, 1883-1919 (Folders 20.34-20.37)
      - Rose, William J., correspondence from, 1870-1878 (Folder 20.38)
      - To Mary Lee Rose from family members including Laura Benét, William Rose Benét, Teresa Benét and Frances Rose Benét, 1862-1937 (Folders 19.9-19.14)
- SERIES V. GRANDPARENTS OF LAURA, WILLIAM, AND STEPHEN, 1872-1895
  - Benét, Laura Walker, correspondence to/from, 1883-1894 (Folders 20.14-20.16)
  - to Benét, Laura Walker from Laurence Benét, 1885-1894 (Folder 20.20)
  - Benét, Stephen Vincent, Sr., correspondence to/from, 1872-1895 (Folder 20.24)
  - to Benét, Stephen Vincent, Sr. from Laurence Benét, undated (Folder 20.21)
  - Correspondence, from (great uncle) Laurence Vincent Benét, to family members, 1882-1888 (Folder 27.3)
- SERIES VI. CHILDREN OF WILLIAM AND STEPHEN, 1920s-1930s
  - Benét, Frances Rosemary, correspondence from, 1926-1935 (Folder 20.10)
  - Benét, James Walker, Jr., correspondence to/from, 1920s-1930s (Folder 20.11)
  - Benét, Kathleen Anne, correspondence from, 1920s-1930s (Folder 20.13)
  - Benét, Stephanie and Thomas, correspondence to family members, 1930s (Folder 20.25)
- SERIES VII. MISCELLANEOUS BENÉT FAMILY MATERIAL, 1803-1969
  - Miscellaneous unidentified correspondence to/from various family members, 1906-1969 (Folders 20.1-20.9)
  - Deteriorated correspondence to various/unidentified Benét family members, 1900s-1930s (Folders 22.1-22.16)
  - Insurance policies, stocks, 1894-1931 (Folder 20.39)
  - Invoices, receipts, 1907-1943 (Folders 20.40-20.44)
  - Real estate holdings, correspondence with J.F. Ellis, Esquire, 1890s (Folder 20.45)
  - Real estate holdings, Laura and William Rose Benét, 1928 (Folder 21.5)
  - Last will and testament, Catherine Neill, Frances Rose Benét, 1899, 1939 (Folder 21.10)
  - Real estate agreement, 1890 (Folder 21.15)
  - Journal, anonymous, 1917 (Folder 21.11)
  - Journal, Mahon, F.E., 1863 (Folder 22.17)
  - Report cards, lists - Benét, William Rose, Kathleen, Frances Rose, Walker, 1870-1928 (Folder 21.13)
  - Writings, unidentified typescripts, manuscripts, undated (Folder 21.14)
  - Journal, [James Walker Benét?], 1920 (Folder 22.18)
  - Printing plate - calling card for Elizabeth Neill Rose, undated (Folder 22.19)
  - Mathematics lesson book, 1803 (Folder 26.1)
  - Photostats from the New York State Library, including an Ada Rehan letter and images of the Old Pearl Street Theatre, 1943 (Folder 27.2)
- SERIES VIII. PHOTOGRAPHIC PRINTS, 1882-1939
  - Photo album - including the Benicia Arsenal and family travels in the west, circa 1905-1911; (fire damaged) (Folder 28.1)
  - Scrapbook - "Benicia Arsenal Views,", circa 1905-1911 (Folder 29.1)
  - Family groups and portraits, undated (Folder 30.3)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified family, undated (Folder 30.4)
  - Unidentified family portrait, undated (Folder 31.24)
  - Laura Benet, undated (Folder 30.1)
  - Laura Benet - Slabsides and Vassar, circa 1904-1907 (Folder 30.5)
  - Stephen Vincent Benet, Rosemary Carr, and their 3 children (as well as Frances Rose Benet and Rachel Hickey Carr), 1938 Spring (Folder 31.4)
  - Stephen Vincent Benet, undated (Folder 32.1)
  - William Rose Benet, undated (Folder 32.3)
  - William Rose Benet - portrait from Albany Academy, circa 1899-1904 (Folder 32.4)
  - Children of Teresa and William Rose Benet, undated (Folder 31.3)
  - Teresa Benet and children [?], undated (Folder 30.2)
  - James Walker Benet, undated (Folder 32.2)
  - Francis Rose Benet, undated (Folder 32.5)
  - Francis Rose Benet - portraits, 1882, 1915 (Folder 32.6)
  - Frances Rose Neill Benet, undated (Folder 31.8)
  - Mary Lee Rose, undated (Folder 32.7)
  - Mrs. Rose, undated (Folder 31.1)
  - Mary Mahon, 1919 (Folder 31.2)
  - Rosemary Benet, aged approximately 2 years, circa 1917 (Folder 32.8)
  - Kathleen and Charles Norris with Frances Rosemary and Kathleen Anne Benet, undated (Folder 32.9)
  - Wedding of Kathleen Anne Benet and George B. Fry II, 1939 August (Folder 31.5)
  - Rachel Lyman Field at 3 years old, 1898 (Folder 31.6)
  - Anna and Marian Watts, 1897, undated (Folder 31.7)
  - Anna Bundy Jacobs, Westtown Farmhouse, Pennsylvania, undated (Folder 31.9)
  - Signed portrait of unidentified author, undated (Folder 32.17)
  - Painting of Helen Parry Eden at 24, undated (Folder 32.11)
  - Friends - named, undated (Folder 32.10)
  - Friends - named, undated (Folder 31.14)
  - Unidentified women photographed in Philadelphia, undated; (cartes des visite) (Folder 31.11)
  - Woman from the Neill Family photographed in Philadelphia, undated; (carte des visite) (Folder 31.12)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified women, undated (Folder 31.13)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified women, undated (Folder 31.15)
  - Unidentified women, undated; (tin types) (Folder 31.10)
  - Unidentified women, undated (Folder 28.2)
  - Portrait of an unidentified woman, undated (Folder 28.7)
  - Portrait of an unidentified woman, undated (Folder 28.8)
  - Portrait of an unidentified man (Laurence V. Benet?), undated (Folder 29.4)
  - Unidentified men, undated (Folder 32.15)
  - Unidentified children - Norwalk, Connecticut, undated (Folder 31.16)
  - Unidentified children - groups, undated (Folder 31.17)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified children, undated (Folder 31.19)
  - Unidentified children, undated (Folder 31.20)
  - Unidentified children, undated (Folder 32.14)
  - Three portraits of unidentified children, including one taken by Walter Scott Shinn, circa 1920, undated (Folder 29.3)
  - Unidentified child, undated; (tintype) (Folder 31.18)
  - Portrait of unidentified child, taken by Philip Conklin, Troy, New York, undated (Folder 32.12)
  - Portrait of unidentified child, framed in Washington, DC, undated (Folder 32.13)
  - Benicia Arsenal, 1907 (Folder 29.3)
  - Rectory of St. Luke's Protestant Episcopal Church, Mechanicsburg, Pennsylvania, 1924 (Folder 31.21)
  - Augusta, Georgia - Flood of [1888?], undated (Folder 31.22)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified buildings and landscapes, undated (Folder 29.2)
  - Unidentified homes, undated (Folder 32.16)
  - Unidentified homes, undated (Folder 31.23)
  - Locations, homes, landscapes, undated (Folder 29.2)
  - Unidentified homes and people, undated (Folder 28.3)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified buildings, undated (Folder 28.4)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified landscapes, undated (Folder 28.5)
  - Negatives, undated; (damaged) (Folder 31.25)
  - Postcards, undated (Folder 28.6)